Take your hands off me!
Your hand was around
his neck. Michael.
If it's not Annie. I
don't want anyone here.
We need to discuss
Dylan's academic work.
So. does this mean I
can't play in the match?
25 grand a year. And for what?
They're punishing you.
I'm angry because of
you! 'Have you seen it?'
"Bradley family claims no
new lead in over a decade"
and "never feeling
like Tina is the priority".
I think about her every
day. She was my friend.
If you were gonna find her...
You'd have done it by now.
Did you kill mum?
Couldn't you have just let her go?
No wonder people are pointing fingers.
No wonder everyone's gone.
I wanted to ask him to his face.
If he killed your mum?
He didn't say anything.
'To be clear. you think he did it?'
he didn't deny it. He just
had this look on his face. like...
Everything was over.
And him saying nothing...
That was his way of
saying that you were right?
No.
No. that's how we got
here in the first place.
He's not capable...
Of saying anything.
Ma'am?
Incident at the school.
Ambulances called.
Annie...
I've been talking to the people here.
They got to him just
in time. And there's this.
It's addressed to you.
"I am to blame for the
death of Sarah Polly."
Not even "the death of my wife".
Sarah Polly.
Like she's someone
who lives down the road.
There's a separation
there. It's not a confession.
It's a tacit confession.
It's an admission he wasn't
enough. That's what he's been saying.
He blames himself for
her death. not her murder.
Annie. you know. sometimes.
the most obvious thing
is the thing that's happened.
More often than not. in fact.
So. once the psychiatrist
says we're allowed in.
we put this to him again.
What he meant by this
note. If he killed Sarah.
I don't think he did.
Then you need to find
a way to eliminate him.
That's allowed now?
I'm back on the team?
You were never off it. I was litter picking.
Logging. Litter logging.
What I'm saying is if you're
so sure that he's innocent.
get out there and prove it. Ok.
Er. no visitors. Not yet. Dad.
Dad! Dad. please!
Dad. please. please...
Listen. please move away.
Please keep away from the door!
I need to know why you did this!
Dad. dad.
Dad. please... Stand back.
Dad. Tell me why.
Dad...
Please sit down.
Now. despite what some
of you might have heard.
there will be no changes
to today's timetable.
Tomorrow. we will host the final
rugby game of the season as planned.
Your attendance at
that. especially at a time
when we could all benefit
from pulling together...
Well. it's positively encouraged.
Whatever's happened over these
past few weeks. however awful.
I want you all to remember
it is not the fault of any of you here.
Here's one for you.
If he murdered her.
Michael. what about his car?
Fine. thanks. Annie. how are you
he'd have had to have move the
body to the woods. wouldn't he?
So. unless he gave her
a piggyback down there.
he would've had to drive.
So what did forensics
say they found in the car?
Nothing. Nothing? Nothing incriminating.
That's what I thought.
Only cos they shared it.
Forensics found plenty of
evidence of Sarah present in the car.
but you'd expect that.
It doesn't prove anything either way.
Are you ok? Yeah.
I don't think he did it.
I've gotten to know him. Duncan.
I've spent a lot of time with him.
And I don't think he's the
person who's killed Sarah.
I'm worried we're gonna end
up charging the wrong guy here.
So you want to show
he couldn't have done it?
Exactly. because if he can't have done it.
he can't have done it.
Even if he says he did. Yes.
Let's look at it all again.
Thank you. That's all right.
It's not so much the car. it's the boot.
He'd have had to put
the body in the boot.
So we're after blood. saliva. hair.
anything that indicates that she...
She was made to lie in the back.
Well. there's no blood... Ok.
Nothing here about any saliva.
421-b and c.
Head hairs belonging to... v1.
Sarah Polly.
Ok. That still doesn't mean he...
It doesn't mean he did anything. does it?
There could've been
hair... There could be hair
on the collar of her jacket. and
she put the jacket in the boot.
Yeah. exactly. on the collar.
That would explain it. yes. It would. yeah.
Like you say. it doesn't prove
anything either way. does it?
Thanks. It's all right.
Does he not want to see me
because of what he did to mum.
or because of what he
tried to do in the woods?
That's what I can't work out.
He told you he did it.
That's what you need to
keep in the front of your mind.
He sat in that car. and he admitted it.
No. he didn't deny it. And that's different.
Well. why would he write that
note? Well. we haven't read any note.
Or do what he tried to do
in the woods? Because...
His wife has been murdered.
and his daughter has
accused him of doing it.
So deny it. He's not like that.
Why not? Because he's
not programmed like that.
He's not a violent man.
He is. according to Trudy.
And Rory. and the detective
he was fighting with outside.
You suspected him too. remember?
I'm trying to work it out. Well. don't.
I'm telling you I'm not
sure. so just support me. ok?
Visitor.
I thought you said she wasn't
allowed to be here any more?
She's not. I need to speak to you. Alana.
I know what people are saying.
What are people saying? That
he attacked one of the boys.
Is that what they're saying?
He was never like that with
us. with me. growing up. He...
He loved mum. He loved her.
And I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I know I came to you.
But now I'm not sure.
and he won't talk to me.
Don't be sorry. Alana. please.
Because I don't think
your dad did it either.
I really don't. ok?
Now. the problem I have
is that I think he wants
people to think he did it.
Michael. we need to talk to you.
But we can't do that here. It
has to happen at the station.
So we need to arrest
you. Do this properly.
Come on now.
Tell us what you meant in that note.
And then you can tell
us what you did to Sarah.
When you did it. We
need your help with that.
When did you move her body.
Michael? Was it in the night?
During the day? Which
day? We need that for the cps.
I can't remember.
Alana came to us. Michael.
If you won't do it for us. do it for her.
Explain.
It was Wednesday.
It would've been a Wednesday.
Wednesday - that's
when he thinks he did it.
'I need you to go through
his diary with his secretary.'
if there's a gap on that
Wednesday. we're close.
But it cuts both ways. If
there's no gap. we rule him out.
Not necessarily.
Ivan. why confess to murder
and give the wrong time?
'Let's just check. ok?'
I'll ring you back when I know.
Lessons are blue. staff meetings red.
Anything else is green.
I mean. it's been the
same routine for years.
There. Wednesday the 25th. It's
the same as every Wednesday.
There's always a gap at four o'clock.
in case we need to put something in.
like a meeting or if he needs to pop out.
Why?
Only you and Michael
have access to this?
Michael never looks at this.
Michael keeps it all up here.
But if you do need to put
something in. something last minute...
And he never looks at this.
then where does that go?
That goes in his diary.
His diary? On his desk... normally.
"No good with technology".
'I know the one you mean.'
found it. got it.
23rd. 24th. 25th.
And?
It just says "keep clear".
This his handwriting or yours? His.
Definitely his.
His. Sorry. what does this mean?
It means I'm gonna
need to take this with me.
For the tape. I am detective
constable nira barker.
Also present... Detective
inspector Ivan pemberley.
Kyra Doyle. appropriate adult.
Michael. you have been arrested
for the murder of your wife. Sarah.
You've been offered a
solicitor. but you've declined.
That is correct? Yes. Michael?
Yes. That's correct.
Michael. I want to be clear.
Nothing you have told us outside
of this room is on the record.
So now is your chance.
given what you've wrote
in your note to ds Cassidy.
to explain everything that has happened.
'So. why don't we start with the Monday.
'the day of the rugby match?
'Then let's talk about Wednesday
'when you set aside time in your diary.
'We do this once. Michael.
then it's over. for everyone.'
ok?
'Do you understand what
we're saying. Michael?'
yes. I understand.
Can I have a word. please?
Yeah. of course.
You better have some massive
fucking bombshell for me...
You can't continue
that interview. No? Why?
Why? Look at him. He's not ok.
Well. the psychiatrist
will disagree with you.
This has all been done
the proper way. Next.
"Next"? Next question.
Listen to yourself. Unless
you don't have a question...
Doesn't matter what
the psychiatrist says.
He's in there with an appropriate adult.
Who's about 15 years
old. I mean. look at him.
Look at him with your
own eyes. for Christ's sake.
Look at the state he's in.
He's carrying a lot of guilt. He's suffering.
He needs support.
"Protect and serve". Do you
remember that? Protect him.
Then if he's done it. we will get to that!
What...?
He wants Annie.
Interview suspended at 13:44.
There's a... there's a
great cafe across the street.
I often go there. you know.
if ever there's half an
hour where I'm not needed.
When we sat here two weeks ago...
When you insisted on seeing a detective.
turned out to be me. I
thought straight away.
"he's a man who's most
likely killed his wife."
"He knows he needs to come and
talk to us before we go and talk to him."
And then there was times where
I was certain you hadn't done it.
Now I don't know what to think.
I tell you who deserves to know the truth.
Alana.
I can't.
You owe her that.
I can't see her.
She's lost her mum. Michael.
Please don't let her lose her dad.
'Because she loves
her dad very. very much.'
We'll be as quick as
we can. I'll call you back.
He wants to talk to you.
None of this is admissible.
It's not even being recorded.
You want us to stop it? I
wouldn't. This is her job.
Family liaison officer.
'There's a difference. isn't there?'
between feeling responsible for a crime
and actually committing it.
That's what Alana deserves
to understand. Michael.
It's better to know her
father killed her mother
than never to find out.
Please tell her.
She's right. dad. Just tell me.
Do you remember I...
I told you about my predecessor?
How he told me not to
let the job overwhelm me.
Well. it didn't just overwhelm me.
It defined me.
What do you mean?
When parents are thinking about...
Sending their children to the school...
I'm the person they look to.
I represent the sort of
man that our school creates.
Serious and strong
and a leader. in charge.
But in the end. that's all I was.
That man.
It wasn't just at school.
It was my whole life.
At home.
So that when your mum needed me...
When she needed me to...
To admit that things were going wrong.
that she needed change...
I wouldn't.
And I wasn't there for her. I wasn't.
Even when we were in the
same house. same room.
And in the end. she stopped trying.
Then we stopped talking.
And I could see her.
I could see my wife.
I knew what was
happening. and I didn't...
I didn't do anything.
I just let it happen.
I didn't know the words. I didn't know...
I didn't know how to let her see me.
And that's not strength. is it?
That's not winning. That's just...
Defeat after defeat.
I failed her.
I failed her as a husband...
And as a partner.
And I failed as a
teacher. and I failed you...
As a father. I'm sorry.
Hello? That gap on the Wednesday.
He was interviewing a
teacher for a languages job.
You sure? 'Yes.'
because I asked him to keep it clear.
Are you 100% positive? 'Yes.'
cos she stormed off. It
was a total bloody disaster.
'But that is not you. That is the school.'
and we have been making
these boys. for all these years.
And we've... we've been...
We've been wrong. I've been wrong.
'And I still am... Pig-headed
and arrogant and...'
and the damage that I've
caused. it's still happening.
Dylan came to me. and he was so angry.
He was angry at me. and...
The affair and the adults
who should know better.
'We're just fucking up his life.'
and what I did...
What I did. I can't...
I can't forgive myself for what happened.
'For what happened to who... dad?'
for what happened to mum?
Did you do it?
Dad.
Please.
Did you do it?
No.
Do you promise? Yes.
Well. then. who did?
If it wasn't you. you
must have some idea.
Who would be this angry with
her? Who would do this to mum?
Dylan.
What if it's Dylan?
We need to tread extremely carefully.
We work with the school.
and we are light touch.
Annie. given how you know the staff.
and Ivan. as sio. you go
down there. but that is it.
This stays amongst us.
No-one breathes this to anyone.
Yeah. It's a theory. nothing more.
And Annie's right. It's
no-one's idea of a good result.
We need to have a conversation.
regarding one of your pupils.
Are you the teacher in charge here?
No. I'm head of the sixth form.
but if you tell me which pupil...
Who is the teacher in
charge? That's mr bowman now.
But he's popped home to get a
trophy for the end of the match.
It's the trophy we were given
when I was a boy at the school.
The last team to go invictus. back in '96.
I thought. at the final
whistle. if we've won the game.
I could present it there and then.
Where in the hell have I...?
Rory. I'm here because I need to
talk to you about Sarah's murder.
I want to ask you about Dylan Sedgwick.
Have a look at his timetable.
ask about his behaviour.
Has it changed in recent weeks?
Obviously. this is a
very sensitive subject.
and nobody's pointing the
finger yet. but we're just...
Well. we're asking for your
help. No. no. no. of course.
I mean. I can't believe
I'm saying this. but...
He's had his problems. Dylan.
aggression issues and so on.
Sorry.
I can barely. er... It's ok.
you can take a minute.
Sarah had an affair with
his father. Awful. slimy guy.
Christ.
He's playing a rugby match now. yes?
We can let them finish. He's not playing.
No. he fell behind academically.
Like I said. he had his issues.
I think we go back.
Let the game finish. let our visitors go.
then we talk to him
and his parents together.
How does that sound? That
sounds great. yes. Thank you.
Give it a slam. It doesn't shut otherwise.
Annie?
Annie. are you in here?
Annie. I can explain.
Ok. good.
Explain.
'You might have misunderstood
what's happened here.'
tell me what's happened here.
I was in those woods.
I went there. yes. but afterwards.
after Sarah's body had been found.
You went there? To look.
And that's where I lost it. the key.
This is about the key? Yeah.
I'm just pleased you found it.
I've been wondering
where on earth I put it...
Why did go to the scene
and not tell anyone?
That's a bit odd. isn't it?
Well. maybe it fell out of my pocket.
Just... just...
I'm not calling anyone.
No-one's coming. There's no back-up.
And I've just switched
that phone off. look.
Just you and me.
You're upset about Sarah.
Look...
She clearly meant a lot you. No. no. no.
Did she mean a lot to you?
We'd known each other for years.
Yeah. he was not what
she deserved. Michael?
I tried to kiss her once.
made a move after a
night out with the teachers.
And she said she
couldn't. that she mustn't.
And she was right cos she was married.
Otherwise. it would've
worked out... Between us.
You know. that's the tragedy.
And when all the crap started.
you know. she looked after me. Sarah.
What crap? Teachers.
Female teachers. One
of them accused me of...
I never... I never did anything.
But I'm a single man.
And if I like someone. why...
Why can't I try and. you know...?
How else does anyone
make their feelings known?
They said it wasn't the only occasion...
And that there'd been a complaint
and that the school
might get a reputation.
that female teachers might not apply.
And she convinced Mike
to give me a final chance.
She was very important to you.
Yes! Yeah.
Yeah?
I've never told anyone that.
And then. er... I noticed the affair.
It was me. not Mike. who spotted
it. so I confronted her about it.
I made her text him.
Sedgwick. saying it was over.
I forced her to do that. for her own good.
And if she can't be with
you. a good man like you.
she can't be with Sedgwick.
If you have an affair with
a parent and that gets out...
She'd have to leave. They both would.
The school would have
suffered. My... my school.
And she lied to me. said
it was over when it wasn't.
said she'd ended it.
So I kept telling her she should stop it
for the sake of the school. for the school.
But she kept shouting.
She kept shouting and shouting! And I...
I...
I wanted her to stop shouting. and...
That's all I wanted.
It needed to stop.
It's...
I never... I'm the last person in the world
who'd ever wanna do anything like that.
I-I really am.
I'm sorry. Sorry.
Rory. from what you're saying.
it sounds more like an accident.
Yeah. You know. stuff goes wrong.
People have arguments.
and things just...
They just get out of hand. don't they?
I mean. I've seen it. Yeah.
I've seen too much of it. but. you know.
I've also seen men like you...
Good men like you have their
lives absolutely ripped to shreds
when it's not their fault.
It wasn't my fault.
We need to talk about this at the station
because I know that you're gonna
want to explain this to them too.
No. I can't. I can't do that.
I understand that this is very scary.
But you have my word. you
are gonna be looked after.
I'm not... I'm not ready.
Listen. Listen to me.
I'm not... I'm not ready. Rory.
you might even find it a relief.
Just to tell the truth just the
way you have with me there.
That's a brave thing to do.
and you are a brave man.
And it is the right thing to do for Sarah.
For Sarah. For Sarah.
Sarah. And do you know
what would be good?
What would be a good way
to tell your story at the station.
is if there was... If there
was some way we could
prove that you didn't have any kind
of problem with Sarah. personally.
I didn't. I loved her. I know.
I can see you loved her very. very much.
But if we are gonna
show that. it would be good
if we could find some
sort of way to prove...
That you were...
Close.
How do we do that?
Er...
Hold on. hold on.
Here.
I have photos.
I could bring these.
This is my first year as
a teacher. here. And...
This is us at the pub. laughing.
And that's me and Sarah together.
There's us holding hands.
I could show you all these.
It's a good plan.
I'm really sor... I'm really sorry.
I'm sorry.
God.
Ok.
It's ok.
Do you know none of
what happened is your fault?
But it's ok to be angry. you
know? We're all fucking angry.
If you want. we can
talk? I don't wanna talk.
I know you don't want to talk. but...
Come on. you're better than
this. sitting in here. all pent up.
Go out there and watch the game.
If they're gonna lose. then
stand there and lose with them.
Go on. Go and do it for yourself.
'Two weeks since the disappearance
'of the teacher Sarah Polly.
and tonight. a major update.
'A man known to mrs
Polly for many years
'arrested on suspicion of her murder.
'With more updates
promised in the coming hours.
'sources close to the investigation
'describe this as a
significant step forward.'
Craig.
You're gonna have to
find a way to tell him. Annie.
Not long after your mum and I met...
She invited me to a
concert in Edinburgh.
This is a recording of that concert.
'Unaccompanied cello
suite no. 1 in g major'
I've been listening to it the...
The last couple of weeks.
It's beautiful. Yeah.
Yes. I always thought so.
And afterwards. we went for a drink...
And your mum said...
She thought we were
at the start of something.
She said she thought
life was about to change.
And she was right.
I. er...
I could feel it.
Was that exciting?
I was terrified.
Because I didn't know what
was going to happen next.
I always get frightened when I don't
know what's going to happen next.
The cellist.
That's your mum.
Hey. How are you?
Well done on the case.
So. here it is.
The full report on the Tina handbag.
The database searches. the forensics.
There's so much new
stuff in here. Annie.
Very excited about where
we're gonna take this next.
Go on.
Come on.
This is a long and complicated
case. this one. Craig.
You're telling me.
This stuff might help. might not. but...
But we won't be doing anything next.
What? Me and you.
Not the Tina Bradley
case. Not on anything.
Annie... We will not
be doing anything next.
It's over. Craig.
It's over.
Subtitles by accessibility@itv.Com